Now previously we learned how to allow the user to set variables using the input and the raw input functions.
These are really handy but I think they make more sense if you want to ask the user for something in
the middle of the execution of the program.
Something similar to what the social engineering toolkit does.
But I think for a simple program like this one it would make more sense if we can get our user to input
the values as arguments.
So what I mean by arguments is itll be cool if we can allow the user to do something like Python.
Mike Mark change your daughter Pyu II and then give me the values by do an interface so to land zero
and then do my work and give me the Neumark.
Now we actually want to implement something like this.
Its not going to be easy because first of all we need to implement some way of reading all of this.
Everything that comes after the command.
We also need to be able to read the option names or the arguments here and we need to read the option
values which is nonzero and then you.
And we also need to display a help message for the person when they don't give arguments or when they
ask for help.
For example with all of the known commands if you just do ifconfig help you'll get a long menu showing
the help and how to use all of the arguments that come with the ifconfig command.
So you can do this.
Its possible that you can write all of this yourself or you can just use an already made module by Python
and that's what we're going to do.
So in order to use a module just like subprocess we need to import that module.
So to do that we're going to do import module name which is to parse so odd parse is the name of the
module that allows us to get arguments from the user and parse them and use them within our code.
Now important the model doesn't mean that your program is going to automatically use it as you can see
it's actually written in gray right now and it's telling us that it's unused because we never used this
module with our code.
So when you import something you tell Python that I'm going to use some code that exists within this
module but you actually have to call it within your code to use it similar to the subprocess when we
call it in here.
So the next step now is to call this module and get our program to recognize user input and parse it
to do this.
We're going to create a parser object so you can think of this object as an entity or a person that
knows everything about parsing and arguments and can handle all of that itself.
So it's a person or an entity that we're going to use in our program that will handle user input for
us.
So to create this object or this entity we're going to say parser equals Obed parse which is the name
of the module that we just imported and we want to create an option parser now parser.
Here is just another variable.
So it's similar to interface and Neumark.
The difference is the value that it holds is different than the value that's held in here.
So for example interface here gets whatever value that is returned by zero input.
And there are impot returns whenever the person enters and the person enters a sequence of characters
for the name of the interface.
So the interface usually holds a value of a string a sequence of characters parser on the other hand
is going to hold the value of whatever over parse that option parser returns.
Now notice the name here starts with a capital letter.
This is a naming convention in Python.
And basically everything that starts with a capital letter means that it is a class and while a class
is it's basically code or you can think of it as rules or a blueprint for the object.
So it determines what we can do with the parser object.
It's basically all the code that can read the user input.
Like I said in here when you do interface for example it's all the code that displays the health message
it's all the code that stores the values that the user enters all of it is stored in the option parser
class which you can't use the class as is.
You need to create an instance of that class.
And that's what we're doing here we're creating an entity or an object and that object is stored in
the parser variable.
Now again we're going to be use an object a lot throughout the course.
And as we use them it will become clearer.
So right now we created an instance of the option parser class which is an object that can handle parsing
for us.
Now you can think of this parser object as a child so it has all the abilities that it inherits from
its father which is the class to handle parsing but since it's a child we still need to tell it what
kind of arguments to look for and how to handle them.
So we're going to start teaching this child by doing parser that option and basically what we're doing
now is we're giving it the first argument that it can expect from users.
So this argument is going to be dush are way to specify the interface.
We're also going to say the user can either give you dush II or they can give you dash dash interface
to specify the interface then we're going to say this equals interface.
And what we're doing.
What we mean by Desk is this is the name where the value of the interface is going to be stored.
So this is how we're going to be retrieving the user input again.
Let's keep doing this and it's going to become clearer once we actually get it done.
Finally we're going to get the help message to display to the user if they require help and we're going
to set that to interface to change.
It's Mike address.
OK.
So it's very very simple so far.
So all we're doing is we're teaching this person or object or child we're telling it that I want you
to allow the user to enter a value that's value they can enter it and they're the dash or dash dash
interface argument whatever value they enter.
I want you to store it on their interface.
And if the user requires help then display this help message to explain what this argument is.
Finally we're going to tell this child to parse the arguments that it gets from the user.
So to do that we're going to say parser dot.
And as you can see when you actually press the dot Percheron will automatically show you all the methods
that you can invoke on this object or this child.
So what we wanted to do is we just wanted to learn or understand what it got so far.
So we wanted to parse arguments.
Now let's go down to our program and all I'm going to do is I'm just going to do Python might change
or that why and I'm just going to do a dash dash help.
OK so this is perfect.
Now because we're use an odd parse and because we created the option parser here you can see that our
program automatically displays and help message when we do dash dash help.
You can see that this message is given us the usage so saying we can use this program by do a mike changer
that p y followed by the options and the options are.
You can either do dash H or dash dash help to see this help message.
Or you can do this option and this option is the first option that we created in here and added using
the ADD option method so you can see that a still must use this option.
You can either use dash or dash dash interface.
So this is what we set in here.
We said to use either dash or dash dash interface.
You can also see the health message that we set in here is being displayed in here telling the user
that you can use this option to set the interface to change its MAC address.
Now this is perfect.
This is exactly what we wanted.
And in the next lecture we'll learn how to add more options to this and how to use the values that the
user input into our program.